Guide to the New York State Teachers Association Records 1915-1979
New York State Teachers Association Records
- Series VII: Professional and Regional Services Files
  - Sub-Series C: Higher Education Files
    - Sub-Series d: Community Collages, 1968-1972
      - Erie CC, 1969-1970 (Box 205, Folder 24)
        draft of contract between ACCF members and college
      - Erie CC, 1969-1971 (Box 205, Folder 25)
        contract-faculty assoc.,
      - Erie CC, 1970 (Box 205, Folder 26)
        2nd draft of contract
      - Erie CC (Box 205, Folder 27)
        Ron Ulba, NYST Rep. control negotiations, 1970
      - Erie CC, 1970-1971 (Box 205, Folder 28)
        (switched from AFT/AFL-CIO) affiliation to (ACCF) NYSTA-misc.
      - Erie CC (Box 205, Folder 29)
        arbitration case-concerning hiring of certain faculty in violation of contract-corres. Re Faculty Assoc., 1971
      - Erie CC, 1972 (Box 205, Folder 30)
      - Erie CC, 1972 (Box 205, Folder 31)
        arbitration decisions concerning state urban center pay rates and continuing education hiring practices, 1972
      - Erie county Technical Institute, 1968-1969 (Box 205, Folder 32)
        agreement, routine corres.
      - CC of the Fingerlakes, 1968-1972 (Box 205, Folder 33)
        NYSTA affiliation efforts-corres. 1968-1972
      - Finger Lakes CC, 1971-1972 (Box 205, Folder 34)
      - Fulton Montgomery CC, 1969-1970 (Box 205, Folder 35)
        Faculty Assoc.-routine corres. And agreements, 1969-70
      - Fulton Montgomery CC, 1970-1971 (Box 205, Folder 36)
      - Fulton Montgomery CC, 1971 (Box 205, Folder 37)
        ACCF negotiations
      - Genesee CC, 1970 (Box 205, Folder 38)
        Faculty Assoc., routine corres., 1970
      - Genesee CC, 1970-1971 (Box 205, Folder 39)
      - Genesee CC, 1971 (Box 205, Folder 40)
      - Herkimer County CC, 1970-1971 (Box 205, Folder 41)
      - Herkimer County CC, 1971-1972 (Box 205, Folder 42)
        re case of J. Pickard-involving non-renewal of teaching contract due to student complain, 1971-1972
      - Herkimer County CC case, 1972 (Box 205, Folder 43)
      - Hudson Valley Community College (Box 206, Folder 1)
        faculty assoc.-routine corres., organizing petition, 1968-69
      - Hudson Valley CC, 1969-1971 (Box 206, Folder 2)
        contract, faculty handbook
      - Hudson Valley CC, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 3)
        grievance settlement re sabbatical leaves; urban center; general info related to contract negotiations, 1971
      - Hudson Valley CC, 1971-1972 (Box 206, Folder 4)
      - Jamestown CC, 1969-1970 (Box 206, Folder 5)
        routine corres., contract, proposed salary schedules, 1969-1970
      - Jamestown CC, 1970-1971 (Box 206, Folder 6)
      - Jamestown CC, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 7)
        salary negotiations
      - Jefferson CC, 1970 (Box 206, Folder 8)
        re faculty association
      - Jefferson CC, 1970-1971 (Box 206, Folder 9)
      - Jefferson CC, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 10)
        Grievance re unilateral charge in bargaining unit
      - Kingsborough CC, 1970-1971 (Box 206, Folder 11)
      - Manhattan CC, 1970-1971 (Box 206, Folder 12)
      - Mohawk Valley CC, 1969-1970 (Box 206, Folder 13)
        PERB Certification Petition, misc. info, routine corres.
      - Mohawk Valley CC, 1970-1971 (Box 206, Folder 14)
      - Mohawk Valley CC, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 15)
      - Mohawk Valley CC, 1971-1972 (Box 206, Folder 16)
      - Mohawk Valley CC, 1971-1972 (Box 206, Folder 17)
      - Monroe CC, 1969-1970 (Box 206, Folder 18)
        re faculty assoc. agreement, routine corres.
      - Monroe CC, 1971-1972 (Box 206, Folder 19)
        grievances
      - Monroe CC, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 20)
      - Nassau CC Faculties, 1969-1970 (Box 206, Folder 21)
      - Nassau CC PERB Matters, 1971-1972 (Box 206, Folder 22)
      - Nassau CC, 1971-1972 (Box 206, Folder 23)
      - Niagara County CC, 1968-1971 (Box 206, Folder 24)
      - Niagara County CC, 1969-1979 (Box 206, Folder 25)
      - Niagara County CC, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 26)
      - Niagara County CC, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 27)
        resolution to affiliate w/ NYSTA
      - North Country CC, 1969-1971 (Box 206, Folder 28)
        faculty members, policies, activities
      - North Country CC, 1969-1971 (Box 206, Folder 29)
        faculty agreements
      - North Country CC, 1970-1972 (Box 206, Folder 30)
      - North Country CC, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 31)
        ACCF Repr. Council Conference, May 1, 1971
      - North country CC, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 32)
        grievance re unilateral promotion decision, routine corres.
      - Onondaga Cc (Box 206, Folder 33)
        AFL affiliation
      - Onondaga CC, 1969-1971 (Box 206, Folder 34)
      - Orange county CC, 1969-1970 (Box 206, Folder 35)
        misc. routines corres.
      - Orange county CC, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 36)
        exclusion of chairman in Barg. Unit
      - Rochester Institute of Technology, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 37)
        re unit determination
      - Rochester Institute of Technology, 1972 (Box 206, Folder 38)
      - Rockland Community College, 1961-1970 (Box 206, Folder 39)
      - Rockland Community College, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 40)
      - Rockland Community College, 1971 (Box 206, Folder 41)
      - Schenectady CC, 1970 (Box 206, Folder 42)
        misc. info on policies and actions; routine corres.
      - Schenectady CC, 1970 (Box 206, Folder 43)
        minutes of faculty assoc. meeting, 1970
      - Schenectady CC, 1970 (Box 207, Folder 1)
      - Schenectady CC, 1970 (Box 207, Folder 2)
        Impasse
      - Schenectady CC, 1970-1971 (Box 207, Folder 3)
      - Schenectady CC, 1970-1971 (Box 207, Folder 4)
      - Schenectady CC, 1970-1972 (Box 207, Folder 5)
      - Schenectady CC, 1970-1972 (Box 207, Folder 6)
      - Schenectady CC, 1970-1972 (Box 207, Folder 7)
      - Schenectady CC, 1971-1972 (Box 207, Folder 8)
      - Suffolk CC, 1968-1972 (Box 207, Folder 9)
      - Suffolk CC, 1968-1972 (Box 207, Folder 10)
      - Suffolk CC, 1968-1972 (Box 207, Folder 11)
      - Suffolk CC, 1970-1971 (Box 207, Folder 12)
      - Sullivan CC, 1970-1972 (Box 207, Folder 13)
      - Sullivan CC, 1970-1972 (Box 207, Folder 14)
      - Sullivan CC, 1970-1972 (Box 207, Folder 15)
      - Tompkins County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 16)
      - Tompkins County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 17)
      - Tompkins County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 18)
      - Tompkins County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 19)
      - Tompkins County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 20)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 21)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 22)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 23)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 24)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 25)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 26)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 27)
      - Ulster County CC, 1969-1972 (Box 207, Folder 28)
      - Westchester CC, 1969-1971 (Box 207, Folder 29)
      - Westchester CC, 1969-1971 (Box 207, Folder 30)
      - Westchester CC, 1969-1971 (Box 207, Folder 31)
    - Sub-Series e: Private Colleges, 1971-1972
      This box contains material relating to the organization of teacher in private colleges. The arrangement is alphabetical by college name.
      - Faculty Association in Private Institutions (Box 208, Folder 1)
        re organizing in private colleges
      - Private Colleges and Universities (Box 208, Folder 2)
      - Columbia University Campaign (Box 208, Folder 3)
        NEA-NYSTA attempt to organize: routine correspondence, 1972
      - Manhattan College Vs. American Assoc. of University Professors, 1971 (Box 208, Folder 4)
        Manhattan College chapter
      - NLRB, 1972 (Box 208, Folder 5)
        re attempt to organize university professional and non-professional employees Syracuse Univ. Vs. Syracuse Univ. Chapter of American Assoc. of Univ. Professors-related info and briefs, 1972
      - Corres. w/out of State Colleges, 1971-1972 (Box 208, Folder 6)
        concerning NYSTA assistance
      - St. John's University (Box 208, Folder 7)
      - Skidmore College, 1971 (Box 208, Folder 8)
        memo
      - Villa Maria college, 1972 (Box 208, Folder 9)
        (buffalo) re petition for union certification (NLRB case)
      - Unit Determination (Box 208, Folder 10)
        University of Detroit, E. Michigan Univ., Fordham Univ., Lansing Community College
      - Unit Determination (Box 208, Folder 11)
        Univ. of New Haven, Wayne Sate University
    - Sub-Series f: Senate Professional Association
      This series contains the records of the Higher Education Division concerning the efforts to establish and administer the Senate Professional Association. Boxes 626 and 627 contain material relating to membership drive and agreements. Original finding aid Box 628 contains unsorted documents..
      - SPA Communicator (Box 208, Folder 12)
      - SPA Legal-Kay Scholar (Box 208, Folder 13)
      - SPA Budget (Box 208, Folder 14)
      - SPA Dues Deduction Records (Box 208, Folder 15)
      - Health Centers (Box 208, Folder 16)
      - SPA Expenses (Box 208, Folder 17)
      - Election (Box 208, Folder 18)
        Expenses-Income
      - SPA Supplies and Equipment (Box 208, Folder 19)
- Series VIII: Research Division
  - Sub-Series A.SSSPPP (Salary Survey), 1964-1970
    Survey of Salary Schedule Provisions for Professional Personnel. This series contains documents collected by the research division while producing the salary schedule summaries and regional analysis of teacher salaries and tracts, salary schedule, questionnaires and tabulation sheets. (Contracts for 1968-1972 have been removed and can be found in the LMDC's PERB collection. The summary reports and regional analysis can be found in the Library's holdings. Check catalogue.) The documents have been arranged by district as follows: The State has been divided into two general areas: Group I-includes the five NYSTA zones around the NYC metropolitan area. Group II-consists of the remaining ten zones. In addition, the districts are separated by the size of the teaching staff (more than fifty, or less than fifty). Moreover, the districts have bee classified by type of district as follows (1) cities-excluding the seven centralized city school districts and NYC. (2) Villages0independent union free and independent central school districts (3) other central school districts including centralized cities. (4)other union free districts with high schools (5) common school districts and union free districts without high schools. The following abbreviations will be used for each type of district (1) upstate city (2) upstate village (3) NYC-metropolitan and NY village (4) up. 50+ (5) up. 50-
    - Upstate Cities/Cities, 1964-1965 (Box 210, Folder 1)
    - Upstate Villages, 1964-1965 (Box 210, Folder 2)
    - NY Villages, 1964-1965 (Box 210, Folder 3)
    - Up 50+, 1964-1965 (Box 211, Folder 1)
      Adams Center-Mayfield
    - Up 50+, 1964-1965 (Box 211, Folder 2)
      Mexico End: Up 50- A-Chadwick, 1964-1965
    - Up 50-, 1964-1965 (Box 211, Folder 3)
      Champlain-End
    - Upstate City Districts, 1964-1965 (Box 212, Folder 1)
    - NY Supervisory Districts, 1964-1965 (Box 212, Folder 2)
    - Survey Data/Placement Sources/Local Studies, 1962-1960 (Box 212, Folder 3)
    - Tabulations of Contract Provisions (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - BOCES, 1965-1966 (Box 213, Folder 2)
      1965-66 Up 50- A-HOU
    - UP 50- LO-WYO Up 50+ PA-YO, 1965-1966 (Box 213, Folder 3)
    - Upstate Villages, 1965-1966 (Box 214, Folder 1)
    - Group I 50-:, 1965-1966 (Box 214, Folder 2)
      Group I Villages
    - Group I: Group II City Districts, 1965-1966 (Box 214, Folder 3)
    - NY Districts 50+, 1965-1966 (Box 215, Folder 1)
    - Group I Villages, 1965-1966 (Box 215, Folder 2)
    - Upstate Districts 50+, 1965-1966 (Box 215, Folder 3)
      A-Lake Shore
    - Upstate Districts 50 +, 1965-1966 (Box 216, Folder 1)
      Lansing-York
    - Group II Upstate 50-, 1966-1967 (Box 216, Folder 2)
      A-LY
    - Group II Upstate 50-, 1966-1967 (Box 216, Folder 3)
      Mad-end/ Upstate 50 + A-Cazenovia
    - Upstate 50+, 1966-1967 (Box 216, Folder 4)
      Ch-Nunda
    - Upstate 50 + Oakfield-end, 1966-1967 (Box 217, Folder 1)
    - Group I Villages, 1966-1967 (Box 217, Folder 2)
      A-Patchogue
    - Group I Villages (Box 217, Folder 3)
      Pearl River-end/ Group I-cities
    - Group I 50+, 1966-1967 (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Upstate Villages, 1966-1967 (Box 218, Folder 2)
    - Group I 50-/ Group II Upstate Cities, 1966-1967 (Box 218, Folder 3)
    - Research Studies/ Administrative Salary Surveys, 1965-1966 (Box 219, Folder 1)
    - Salary Summary Work shifts, 1967 (Box 219, Folder 2)
    - Extra Pay, Administrative Other Personnel Analysis, 1966-1967 (Box 219, Folder 3)
      Tax expenditures
    - Cities, 1956-1957 (Box 219, Folder 4)
    - Villages, 1956-1957 (Box 220, Folder 1)
    - Small Districts, 1956-1957 (Box 220, Folder 2)
      NYC Area Complete/ Upstate A-Harrisville
    - Small Districts UP, 1956-1957 (Box 220, Folder 3)
      Hartford-end, 1956-57
    - Large Districts Ad-Katonah, 1956-1957 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Large Districts Lake Shore- end, 1956-1957 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - Group I Villages, 1967-1968 (Box 221, Folder 3)
    - Group II 50+/ Group II Up 50- Ab- INT, 1967-1968 (Box 222, Folder 1)
    - Group II Up 50- Jas - end/ Group II Boces, 1967-1968 (Box 222, Folder 2)
    - Group I Villages Ard-Lyn, 1967-1968 (Box 222, Folder 3)
    - Group I Villages Mam-end, 1967-1968 (Box 223, Folder 1)
    - Group I 50 + Am-So, 1967-1968 (Box 223, Folder 2)
    - Group II Villages Ma-end, 1967-1968 (Box 223, Folder 3)
    - Group II 50 + A-Hous, 1967-1968 (Box 224, Folder 1)
    - Group II 50 +, 1967-1968 (Box 224, Folder 2)
      Spencerport
    - Group II Cities (UP), 1967-1968 (Box 224, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series B. Interview Studies of Select Districts., 1970
    This series contains the results of fifteen interview studies in various school districts in New York State. Both NYSTA members and non-members were interviewed. The studies were designed to determine the attitude of NYS teachers toward NYSTA, their suggestion for and criticism of NYSTA programs, the specific problem areas in which they felt NYSTA could be of service to public education. The Are arranged alphabetically by District name. This description is for original box 678.
    - Research, 1965-1966 (Box 225, Folder 1)
      Salary Report Series
    - Research, 1965-1966 (Box 225, Folder 2)
      Special Memoranda
    - NYSTA Helps for Teacher Salary Studies Bulletin, 1966 (Box 225, Folder 3)
    - Research Dept. Study Series: Comparisons of NYS Teachers, Employees and NYC Teachers Retirement Systems, 1966 (Box 225, Folder 4)
    - Research Dept. Preliminary Report: In service Training, 1966 (Box 225, Folder 5)
    - Research Dept. Information Publications and Research Service Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 225, Folder 6)
    - Research Dept. Personnel and Policies Series, 1965-1966 (Box 225, Folder 7)
    - Research Dept. Public School Finances, 1965-1967 (Box 225, Folder 8)
      Series
    - Anonymous Newsletters, 1957 (Box 225, Folder 9)
      with clippings concerning political issues (union involvement with) 1957
    - Research Dept. Salary Schedule Information Series, 1965-1966 (Box 225, Folder 10)
    - Research Dept. Basic Economic Statistics For Teachers, 1968-1969 (Box 225, Folder 11)
    - Research Dept. Area Reports of Teachers Salary Schedules, 1967-1969 (Box 225, Folder 12)
    - Auburn (Box 225, Folder 13)
    - Baldwin (Box 225, Folder 14)
    - Bayshore (Box 225, Folder 15)
    - Buffalo (Box 225, Folder 16)
    - East Greenbush (Box 225, Folder 17)
    - East Penfield (Box 225, Folder 18)
    - Hicksville (Box 225, Folder 19)
    - Kingston (Box 225, Folder 20)
    - Mastic (Box 225, Folder 21)
    - North Syracuse (Box 225, Folder 22)
    - Patchogue (Box 225, Folder 23)
    - Port Washington (Box 225, Folder 24)
    - Scarsdale (Box 225, Folder 25)
    - Sodus (Box 225, Folder 26)
    - Vestal (Box 225, Folder 27)
- Series IX: New York State Teachers (NYSUT), 1972
  - Unsorted Material (NYSUT) (Box 225, Folder 28)